<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 13:30:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Social Media Case Study: Take a ride with Wobybi</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 13:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21230</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Meet Wobybi, this week’s featured PrestaShop merchant. We sat down with Alvaro Basterra, the company’s founder, to learn more about how they use social media to promote their online store. Let’s find out what he has to say! Tell us about Wobybi. Wobybi is a custom bike brand based in Spain. We are specialized in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/">Social Media Case Study: Take a ride with Wobybi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Meet <a href="http://www.wobybi.es/" target="_blank">Wobybi</a>, this week’s featured PrestaShop merchant. We sat down with Alvaro Basterra, the company’s founder, to learn more about how they use social media to promote their online store. Let’s find out what he has to say!<br />
<span id="more-21230"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Tell us about Wobybi.</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.wobybi.es/" target="_blank">Wobybi</a> is a custom bike brand based in Spain. We are specialized in building one-of-a kind bikes, so our online store, which runs on PrestaShop 1.5.2, has been designed to allow every customer to design their own bike. They first pick a base model, then customize each piece in their preferred color, and finally review and confirm their order. </p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">How has social media impacted your business?</h2>
<p>Social networks are a great way to meet and connect with our community. We try to build a personal relationship with our fans. We like to encourage them to interact with us and comment, share, and send us their pictures and videos.</p>
<p>Because we sell personalized products, interacting with our community is particularly important. We use it to provide unique, exclusive and personal service to each of our customers.</p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Which social media channels and tools do you use?</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/Wobybi" target="_blank">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://www.instagram.com/wobybi/" target="_blank">Instagram</a> work well because they are very visual and enable us to showcase our product photos. We also use <a href="https://twitter.com/wobybi" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, but more as a portal for customer service and sharing information. </p>
<p>Our favorite tools include: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li><a href="https://hootsuite.com/" target="_blank">Hootsuite</a> to schedule publications</li>
<li><a href="https://sumall.com/" target="_blank">SumAll</a> to receive a daily and weekly summary of notifications</li>
<li><a href="https://mention.com/en/" target="_blank">Mention</a> to learn more about people who mention us</li>
<li><a href="https://feedly.com/i/welcome" target="_blank">Feedly</a> to read news on our sector</li>
<li><a href="https://bitly.com/" target="_blank">Bitly</a> to shorten URLs and monitor the number of clicks</li>
</ul>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Where do you get inspiration for social media content?</h2>
<p>We have someone dedicated to managing all of our social media channels full time. Our posts are based on a strategy we’ve defined in our marketing plan: our goal is to create original and quality content to attract new potential customers. Ideas and inspiration can come from anywhere &#8212; Instagram, Pinterest, meetings, brainstorming. The most important thing for merchants to remember is to focus campaigns and not forget about the ultimate goal!</p>
<h2 style="color:#88ae01">Can you share some tips with other merchants starting out on social media? </h2>
<p>The most important thing is to establish a strategy for each social network and only focus on a couple in the beginning; there’s no use just “being there to be there.” Include top quality content tailored to your specific customer base. We use a lot of content that features GIF or videos, which suits our demographic very well. Finally, and most importantly, respond to each question and comment you receive on social media.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Ready to launch your own social media campaign for your ecommerce business? Check out part 1 of our series with HootSuite Social Media Coach for DACH &amp; UK, Hanna Oeljeschlaeger, <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/support-ecommerce-business-social-media/">on supporting your ecommerce business with social media</a>.</p>
<p>Don’t own an online store yet? What are you waiting for get started to day with <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/" target="_blank">PrestaShop</a>. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/">Social Media Case Study: Take a ride with Wobybi</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/social-media-case-study-take-ride-wobybi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Retargeting Basics for Online Merchants</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 13:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21219</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As online shoppers, we’ve all experienced it: while window shopping on a website, you decide you’re not quite ready to make a purchase and go back to skimming Buzzfeed articles. As you continue to browse the internet, you notice the products you just finished browsing hovering at the edge of your screen. How did this [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/">Retargeting Basics for Online Merchants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As online shoppers, we’ve all experienced it: while window shopping on a website, you decide you’re not quite ready to make a purchase and go back to skimming Buzzfeed articles. As you continue to browse the internet, you notice the products you just finished browsing hovering at the edge of your screen. How did this website know you were just ogling those products? If you’re an online merchant, you probably can’t help but ask yourself, would this work for <em>my</em> <a href="http://prestashop.com/">online store</a>? The answer is yes, probably. We invited Garrett Gan from <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/" target="_blank">Thalamus</a>, a digital advertising review website, to give us his insight.<br />
<span id="more-21219"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">1. What is Retargeting?</h2>
<p>Retargeting is a type of advertising that is only shown to people after they have visited your online store. Here’s how it works: you place a pixel (or a single line of code) on your website, which will drop a tracking cookie onto a user&#8217;s browser. With this tracking cookie, <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/display/retargeting" target="_blank">retargeting companies</a> are able to see where the user travels across multiple websites on the internet, and serve them ads accordingly. </p>
<p>The best analogy for this is the tracking of animals using tags, which allows scientists to observe their behavior; in this case, the tag is placed on a consumer&#8217;s&#8217; web browser so that later on, you can serve ads that correspond to their behavior. </p>
<p>One of the best use cases for retargeting is to serve ads to users that have looked at a specific product on your website &#8211; shoes, jeans, t-shirts, trinkets &#8211; and serve them ads for that exact product after they have left (and haven&#8217;t bought yet) with a small discount to entice them to come back to complete the purchase. </p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">2. What types of companies use retargeting? Why?</h2>
<p>All types of companies use retargeting, including those in eCommerce, mobile apps, B2B sites &#8212; even advertising companies!</p>
<p>Retargeting is a powerful tool for communicating with users that have already interacted with your website, to further add value to their experience. </p>
<p>It also makes their web browsing experience more relevant, as the ads you serve will be for specific items they have already browsed, now with discounts and/or giveaways. Without this technology, merchants are now left to decide which products could be relevant for a user. </p>
<p>When retargeting first came out, it was sometimes seen by consumers as “creepy,” but many companies have adopted the tactic for years and has come to be a rather widely accepted practice.</p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">3. How much does it cost to run a retargeting campaign?</h2>
<p>Online merchants can start for as low as $100 per week (or even less) with companies like <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/adroll" target="_blank">AdRoll</a>, or <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/retargeter" target="_blank">Retargeter</a>. There are also larger companies like <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/tellapart" target="_blank">TellApart</a>, <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/criteo" target="_blank">Criteo</a>, or <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/ad_partners/simpli-fi" target="_blank">Simpli.fi</a> that offer more robust features like dynamic creative optimization (changing ads algorithmically to serve the highest performing one), or Product Catalog Feeds (where a consumer can see items similar to the item they just viewed on the e-commerce website).</p>
<h2 style="color:#353466">4. How can online merchants get started with retargeting?</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s a good practice for merchants of all sizes to start running year-round retargeting campaigns. Many eCommerce companies have increased the number of actual conversions from consumers, simply by offering a small discount in a retargeting ad if a user abandoned their cart.</p>
<p>Once merchants are more familiar with how to maximize conversions from regular retargeting ads, then they can move to more sophisticated mechanisms, such as dynamic creative optimization, product feed catalogs (both mentioned above), as well as working with <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/display/ad-network" target="_blank">ad networks</a> to drive new customers to the site.</p>
<hr align="left" width="20%">
<p>Get started today by checking out reviews on retargeting companies like AdRoll and Retargeter on <a href="http://www.thalamus.co/" target="_blank">Thalamus</a>. Then jump in and launch your first retargeting campaign. Already running a campaign? Share your tips and advice in the comments below. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/">Retargeting Basics for Online Merchants</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/retargeting-basics-online-merchants/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>First steps to using video on Social Media</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/first-steps-using-video-social-media/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/first-steps-using-video-social-media/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 11:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all done it: one minute, you’re having a quick scroll through Facebook, and the next you’re 30 minutes into a video binge. You’re living proof: videos not only help attract customers’ attention, but when done correctly, they can help companies build up their brand on social media. Today, find out how you can start [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/first-steps-using-video-social-media/">First steps to using video on Social Media</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’ve all done it: one minute, you’re having a quick scroll through Facebook, and the next you’re 30 minutes into a video binge. You’re living proof: videos not only help attract customers’ attention, but when done correctly, they can help companies build up their brand on social media. Today, find out how you can start using video on social media to grow your own presence.<br />
<span id="more-21221"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#e07531">Pick a platform</h2>
<p>Before you even hit “record,” you’ll need to decide where you want to share your content. The platform you choose will determine the length of your video and vice versa. Let’s start with the most popular: </p>
<h4><a href="https://vine.co/" target="_blank">Vine</a></h4>
<p>This social media network was purchased by Twitter in 2012. What makes Vine unique is that it supports extremely short videos; the target audience is generally under the age of 20. Following the aquisition, 1 in 5 Vine videos are also shared on Twitter, slightly increasing merchants’ reach. <strong>Max Video Length: 6 seconds</strong></p>
<h4><a href="https://www.instagram.com/" target="_blank">Instagram</a></h4>
<p>With Instagram, you get the best of both image and video. In 2010, the company hoped to be the image-sharing platform of this generation. With <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2013/06/20/instagram-users/" target="_blank">130 million monthly users</a>, they aimed to do the same for video in <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/06/20/facebook-instagram-video/" target="_blank">2013</a> by allowing users to upload videos to their feed. If you already have a solid Instagram following, you’ll have no problem adding videos. <strong>Max Video Length: 15 seconds</strong></p>
<h4><a href="https://www.facebook.com/" target="_blank">Facebook</a></h4>
<p>Facebook’s <a href="http://newsroom.fb.com/news/2015/09/introducing-360-video-on-facebook/" target="_blank">the 360 video</a> was hands down the coolest video innovation of 2015. Facebook users can now watch videos and explore them from all 360 angles by simply tilting or rotating their mobile device. Push the envelope while building your Facebook brand: what more could you ask for? <strong>Max Video Length: 3 minutes or 180 seconds</strong></p>
<h4><a href="http://twitter.com/" target="_blank">Twitter</a></h4>
<p>Like Vine, Twitter also allows users to post videos and host them directly from the app. These videos can be longer and uploaded directly from the app. They are accompanied by a tweet for increased shareability. <strong>Max Video Length: 30 seconds</strong></p>
<h4><a href="https://www.youtube.com/" target="_blank">YouTube</a></h4>
<p>Possibly the biggest advantage of using YouTube is its connection with Google. If you create DIY videos or great tutorials, having great SEO linked to them can help you rank high in search results and acquire new potential customers. The second benefit is your ability to rake in additional income (from YouTube’s ads) with increased video views. <strong>Max Video Length: 15 minutes for 900 seconds</strong></p>
<h4><a href="https://vimeo.com/" target="_blank">Vimeo</a></h4>
<p>Dubbed the more “professional” version of <a href="http://mashable.com/2013/05/30/vimeo-over-youtube/#9fEYcbGXjkqD" target="_blank">YouTube</a>, Vimeo allows users to pay for additional features, a key feature of their business model. Because Vimeo doesn’t rely on ads for revenue, your customers don’t have to watch any ads before they get to your content. If you’re putting out short videos of cinematic quality, consider using Vimeo. <strong>Max Video Length: None / Video (Up to 25 GB a year)</strong></p>
<h2 style="color:#e07531">Ideas for social media videos</h2>
<p>Now that you know how long you want your videos to be, you should decide what type of content you want to produce. Here are a few ideas to get you started: </p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Tell a Story.</strong> &#8211; Think of this as a short feature film. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qOIdI_kZNBU" target="_blank">Extra Gum</a> did a tremendous job at telling a story (related to their product) and giving everyone who watched the short film the love chills.</li>
<li><strong>Customer Stories</strong> (user generated content) &#8211; Share some of your current customers’ experiences with the potential customers you want to reach. It’s great if you can interview current customers yourself, but you could also follow <a href="https://www.facebook.com/gopro/videos" target="_blank">GoPro</a>’s lead and encourage customers to submit their best videos.</li>
<li><strong>Behind the Scenes</strong> (or documentary) &#8211; Give customers a look behind your well-oiled doors. If you hand craft your own products, show how they’re made. Put together a photoshoot or lookbook, or share a peek with customers like NYC- based <a href="https://vimeo.com/25439223" target="_blank">Crystal Cactus</a> did.</li>
<li><strong>Guest or Staff Interviews.</strong> Ask questions to another expert, or switch it up and have your followers be the interviewer and you become the interviewee, answering the questions they have (like we did with our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/prestashop/videos/1227558680594405/?theater" target="_blank">#EQM Facebook Campaign</a>).</li>
<li><strong>How to Videos</strong> &#8211; Don’t think you can teach something in just a few seconds? Let Oreo prove you wrong with a <a href="https://v.cdn.vine.co/r/videos/48133739-9554-456A-9AF9-803F42B521B5-618-00000112A175BA3D_1.0.7.mp4?versionId=NQv5RUjDw9AoOKfUOz8lEONNRqJZ3CxV" target="_blank">Vine about making Sprinkles</a>. You’re an expert in your product, so use videos to teach customers a new skill.</li>
<li><strong>Education / History</strong> &#8211; Use videos to teach your social community something. <a href="https://twitter.com/generalelectric/status/683089956277886977" target="_blank">GE</a> uses their infatuation with science to share their geeky wisdom. In this video, they show different ways people have used technology to change the world.</li>
<li><strong>3D / Stop motion / cartoon animations</strong> &#8211; Check out this stop motion animation by PrestaShop Store <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/_o6pdjDv0S/" target="_blank">SelfPackaging</a>. This holiday theme really tapped into holiday season cheer. Afterall, who wouldn&#8217;t want Santa to stop by their home?</li>
</ol>
<p>Now you have the tools you need to start using video marketing on social media. What are you waiting for? His the record button and get started! Already using video on social media? Share your tips in the comments below. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/first-steps-using-video-social-media/">First steps to using video on Social Media</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/first-steps-using-video-social-media/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="https://v.cdn.vine.co/r/videos/48133739-9554-456A-9AF9-803F42B521B5-618-00000112A175BA3D_1.0.7.mp4" length="916512" type="video/mp4" />
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lookbook: Ecommerce Design Inspiration for 2016</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 14:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juan Manuel Molina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21206</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The most successful PrestaShop online stores all have something in common: well thought-out design and outstanding images for backgrounds and products. The 2016 PrestaShop Lookbook features a selection of 24 examples of carefully chosen user interfaces, intelligent and use of color, and best practices, all of which drive conversions. Find inspiration in the most elegant [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/">Lookbook: Ecommerce Design Inspiration for 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The most successful PrestaShop online stores all have something in common:</strong> well thought-out design and outstanding images for backgrounds and products.</p>
<p>The 2016 PrestaShop Lookbook features a selection of 24 examples of carefully chosen user interfaces, intelligent and use of color, and best practices, all of which drive conversions.<span id="more-21206"></span></p>
<p>Find inspiration in the most elegant PrestaShop online stores as you feast your eyes on our unique ecommerce art gallery!</p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn btn-sucess" style="background-color: #2f2f2f;border: 1px solid #191717;border-bottom: 3px solid #292727;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/lookbook" target="_blank"><i class="fa fa-download"></i>   Download the Lookbook</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/">Lookbook: Ecommerce Design Inspiration for 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The merchant&#8217;s guide to Super Bowl 50</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 13:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Super Bowl is the crowning night of America’s favorite pastime. Each year, football fans tune in to see who will take home the coveted Vince Lombardi Trophy, and the rest of America hangs around for the legendary commercials. Whether you’re a die-hard fan or dread Sunday nights in winter, we’re sharing 5 marketing ideas [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/">The merchant&#8217;s guide to Super Bowl 50</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Super Bowl is the crowning night of America’s favorite pastime. Each year, football fans tune in to see who will take home the coveted Vince Lombardi Trophy, and the rest of America hangs around for the legendary commercials. Whether you’re a die-hard fan or dread Sunday nights in winter, we’re sharing 5 marketing ideas to help you score some sales this Super Bowl 50.<br />
<span id="more-21183"></span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#2b5201">Remind me again why I should care about the Super Bowl?</h2>
<p>The Super Bowl is the <a href="http://www.nfl.com/" target="_blank">National Football League</a>’s annual championship game. Aside from being football’s largest televised event each year, with over 100 million viewers, it’s also famous for the high price tag on its 30-second ads. This year, that price is said to be about <a href="http://fortune.com/2015/08/06/super-bowl-ad-cost/" target="_blank">$5 million per 30 seconds</a> (whoever said time is money, is right!). The high price pushes companies to pull out all the stops so their ad makes an impact. Each year the NFL also invites artists to perform during their 30-minute half-time show. Performers like Coldplay, Bruno Mars, and Beyonce are expected to make an appearance this year. </p>
<h2 style="color:#2b5201">Colors</h2>
<p>This year, the <a href="http://www.panthers.com/" target="_blank">Carolina Panthers</a> will be facing off against the <a href="http://www.denverbroncos.com/" target="_blank">Denver Broncos</a>. Even if you didn’t manage to score an advertising spot this year, you can tailor your onsite marketing efforts to catch the attention of sports fans or people in their entourage. Just like at Christmas or Valentine’s, you can make a few graphic design tweaks to get your site in the spirit and capitalize on Super Bowl fever. Each team’s colors are listed below for some inspiration: </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/broncos-300x174.png" alt="broncos" width="300" height="174" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-21185" /></p>
<p><strong>Broncos: <span style="color:#de6226">Orange</span>, <span style="color:#13264b">Navy Blue</span>, <span style="color:#fff;background-color:#000">White</span></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/panthers-300x300.png" alt="panthers" width="300" height="300" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-21184" /></p>
<p><strong>Panthers: <span style="color:#009ada">Panther Blue</span>, <span style="color:#000016">Black</span>, <span style="color:#d1d2d4">Silver</span>, <span style="color:#fff;background-color:#000">White</span></strong></p>
<p>To see this in action, check out <a href="https://www.covergirl.com/collections/nfl-collection" target="_blank">CoverGirl, an NFL sponsor</a>. They do a great job of targeting their products to the non-traditional sports fan (in other words, yes, women like football, too). Merchants selling apparel and accessories can easily promote products for fans to wear to show their support at the stadium or house party. </p>
<p>If you’re a merchant selling food-related goodies, you’re also in luck. Although football is an all-American sport, tickets for this particular event start in the thousands, out of reach of many Americans. Most people (like me) will be enjoying the game from a Super Bowl Party. This means it’s time to feature your fruit tray and promote easy-to-serve finger foods that fans can either bring to or serve at these parties. </p>
<p>If these aren’t options for you, try just interacting with customers on your social media pages. Succeeding in social media is not always about making the conversation about your brand. It’s just as important to participate in the conversation. Root for your favorite team or ask your fans on social media to chime in. You could consider holding a friendly social-only competition with small discounts or exclusive product giveaways as the prize.</p>
<h2 style="color:#2b5201">The Lingo:</h2>
<p>A few words you’ll hear (and can use in your marketing campaigns): </p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Touchdown:</strong> Football’s term for a goal. Each touchdown is worth 6 points, and the opportunity to score 1 additional point or Extra Point (by kicking it between the posts) or 2 additional points 2 point conversion (by running or passing the ball in again.)</li>
<li><strong>Field Goal:</strong> The only other way to score a point. A kicker must kick the ball between the posts to to receive 3 points.</li>
<li><strong>Rings:</strong> Although the winning team receives a trophy, each player receives an additional Super Bowl Ring. Cam Newton: 0, Peyton Manning: 1.</li>
<li><strong>Kick Off:</strong> The game officially starts Sunday, February 7 at 6:30 PM. And since most of us won’t be in attendance, we’ll be watching it on CBS.</li>
<li><strong>Quarterback (QB):</strong> This year, Cam Newton and Peyton Manning are the leading men&#8211;they get to throw the ball.</li>
<li><strong>Interception:</strong> When the opposing team catches the ball instead of the intended receiver. Great for the team that caught the ball, bad for the team who (mis)threw the ball.</li>
<li><strong>Dab:</strong> The dance quarterback Cam Newton does after he completes a successful touchdown. Great to know, when you see <a href="https://media.giphy.com/media/ga3AL3ZPcywec/giphy.gif" target="_blank">GIFs of him dancing</a> on the field all over social media.</li>
</ol>
<p>So there you have it, your merchant guide to enjoying Super Bowl 50. Whether you choose to take advantage of these tips this year, or just enjoy the game, we’ll see you at Kickoff! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/">The merchant&#8217;s guide to Super Bowl 50</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Essential Tips For Launching A Profitable Rewards Program [Infographic]</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21198</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you launch a store, your focus should be on customer acquisition. But at some point, your traffic and sales will start to plateau. If you’re at that point already, it’s time to turn your attention to customer retention. Today’s guest blogger, Darren DeMatas, co-founder of Selfstartr, an ecommerce consulting company helping merchants launch their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/">3 Essential Tips For Launching A Profitable Rewards Program [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>When you launch a store, your focus should be on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/">customer acquisition</a>. But at some point, your traffic and sales will start to plateau. If you’re at that point already, it’s time to turn your attention to <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/">customer retention</a>. Today’s guest blogger, Darren DeMatas, co-founder of <a href="https://selfstartr.com/" target="_blank">Selfstartr</a>, an ecommerce consulting company helping merchants launch their ideas and achieve their goals, tells you how.</em><br />
<span id="more-21198"></span><br />
A go-to retention strategy for many ecommerce businesses is to launch a rewards program. Why not? The average U.S. consumer is enrolled in over 13 loyalty programs! Tapping into your existing customer base makes a lot of sense:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>It is 6X more expensive to acquire a new customer than it is to keep one</li>
<li>The probability of converting an existing customer is 10X higher than a new prospect</li>
<li>Current customers spend 67% more than new ones</li>
</ul>
<p>The <a href="http://selfstartr.com/customer-loyalty-programs/" target="_blank">customer loyalty infographic from Selfstartr</a> shows that these programs can generate ROI if you take the right approach.  Here are three essential tips to launch a profitable rewards program that builds true loyalty.</p>
<h2 style="color:#de166c">1. Reward For Engagement</h2>
<p>Almost all loyalty programs reward customers for spending money (97%). But only 25% reward customers for engagement. It’s no wonder that 77% of them fail within two years.</p>
<p>Customers want to build a relationship that goes beyond money.  Prestashop loyalty add-ons like <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/referral-loyalty-programs/4414-all-in-one-rewards-loyalty-sponsorship-affiliation-fb.html" target="_blank">All-in-one Rewards</a> make this possible. In addition to purchases, you can reward customers for referring their friends to your site through blogs and social media.  This add-on allows you to easily give points for likes. Showing up on your customers’ Facebook wall helps expand your presence and create engagement.</p>
<p>Under Armour is a fantastic example of engagement-based rewards. They give customers points in exchange for exercising and healthy eating.</p>
<h2 style="color:#de166c">2. Don’t Make The Focus On Discounts</h2>
<p>71% of loyalty program members earn more than $100K/year. Not too shabby. While we all like a good deal, it’s safe to say that a saving an extra few bucks won’t really drive customers to purchase. According to Harvard Business professor Gerald Zaltman, <a href="http://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/the-subconscious-mind-of-the-consumer-and-how-to-reach-it" target="_blank">95% of our purchase decision</a> process occurs in the subconscious mind.</p>
<p>So price isn’t necessarily the first barrier you should try to overcome. Often, customers are not sure what product to buy. Clear contact information, links to customer service policies and live chat can help boost buyer confidence.</p>
<p>Show your customers you’re there for them, not just to collect money.</p>
<h2 style="color:#de166c">3. Show Customers That You’re Loyal To Them</h2>
<p>Show customers that you care about them more than their money. Make <a href="https://selfstartr.com/.%C2%A0https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-best-ways-to-build-customer-loyalty-for-your-online-store/" target="_blank">customer service friendly and accessible</a>, even for non-paying customers. You can save your product rewards for high dollar clients, but everyone deserves top notch service.</p>
<p>73% of consumers feel that loyalty programs are for businesses to show their loyalty to customers. The customer is always right, right? Treat them like you want them to come back and they actually might.</p>
<div style="clear:both">
	<a href="https://selfstartr.com/true-value-of-customer-loyalty-programs/" target="_blank"><br />
		<img src="https://2y3k762v0f153f3cbu4efo8g-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Value-Of-Customer-Loyalty.png" title="The True Value Of Customer Loyalty Programs" alt="The True Value Of Customer Loyalty Programs" border="0" /><br />
	</a>
</div>
<p>Courtesy of: <a href="https://selfstartr.com" target="_blank">Selfstartr</a></p>
<p>If you’re looking to improve your customer lifetime value, be sure to check out all the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/503-referral-loyalty-programs" target="_blank">reward program add-ons</a> from Prestashop.</p>
<p>Darren has an MBA in Internet Marketing, but hangs his hat on a decade of experience in the trenches. Check out <a href="https://selfstartr.com/" target="_blank">Selfstartr</a> to learn more about ecommerce. Follow him on <a href="https://twitter.com/DarrenDeMatas" target="_blank">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/internetmarketingmba" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/">3 Essential Tips For Launching A Profitable Rewards Program [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get ready for spring with our partner Amazon Payments</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 13:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In the wake of Snowzilla, we’re all looking forward to leaving the cold, grey season behind us. In the spirit of warmer weather to come, our partner Amazon Payments has launched its “Bring On Spring” campaign this week. Merchants who register a new account by February 15th and make the Amazon Payments module commercially available [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/">Get ready for spring with our partner Amazon Payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the wake of Snowzilla, we’re all looking forward to leaving the cold, grey  season behind us. In the spirit of warmer weather to come, our partner Amazon Payments has launched its “Bring On Spring” campaign this week. Merchants who register a new account by February 15th and make the Amazon Payments module commercially available in their online shop until March20th will pay no service fees during spring 2016. <a href="https://go.amazonservices.com/BoS_UK.html?ld=%20SPUKAP_BOS_B_PS" target="_blank">Click here to learn more</a>.<br />
<span id="more-21178"></span></p>
<h4 style="color:#f6b415">Amazon Payments &#8211; what do they do?</h4>
<p>For those unfamiliar with Amazon Payments, here is a brief overview: the company offers an online payment system that allows millions of Amazon customers to log in and pay on your site with the account information stored in their Amazon accounts. Customers no longer need to remember usernames and passwords, and there is no need to key in credit card and address information again either. Widgets ensure that buyers do not leave the merchant site during the purchasing process, therby ensuring a consistent brand experience.</p>
<h4 style="color:#f6b415">Easy to integrate</h4>
<p>You can activate Login and Pay with Amazon conveniently in your PrestaShop Back Office. To download the plugin file – if necessary – and get further information about the module, please visit the <a href="https://payments.amazon.co.uk/sp/prestashop?ld=%20SPUKAP_BOS_B_PS" target="_blank">Amazon Payments website</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/">Get ready for spring with our partner Amazon Payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2016 Web Design Trends for your Online Store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21163</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Trends come and go, and in the ecommerce industry, where updating web page design is as simple as swapping out a few lines of code, they can shift in an instant. To help guide your web design changes this year, we’ve asked members of our Agency Program to share their predictions for 2016 so you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/">2016 Web Design Trends for your Online Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trends come and go, and in the ecommerce industry, where updating web page design is as simple as swapping out a few lines of code, they can shift in an instant. To help guide your web design changes this year, we’ve asked members of our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/certification-details">Agency Program</a> to share their predictions for 2016 so you can stay ahead of the pack.<br />
<span id="more-21163"></span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#1b9743">Trends from 2015</h2>
<p>First, let’s look at some 2015 trends that are sticking around. If your redesigned your website last year using any of these elements, you don’t have to change them. Armando Salvador, <strong>Chief Technical Officer</strong> at <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/es/asociados-agencia-web/plata/ecomm360">eComm360</a> predicts these trends are here to stay: </p>
<p><strong>Flat Design</strong><br />
Flat web design removes all traces of shadows, depth effects, bevels, gradients and three-dimensional effects to give a simple, minimalist look. This trends makes a website very clean and clear, and a seamless match for responsive design. Although this trend has been around for a few years already, we will continue to see it used in 2016.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/flat-desingquerolets-1024x506.png" alt="flat desing(querolets)" width="700" height="345" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21164" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.querolets.net/es/" target="_blank">Querolets</a></p>
<p><strong>Scroll to tell stories</strong><br />
In 2015, we saw a rise of web pages that seem to scroll to infinity. The scrolling web design not only gives great results, it’s perfect for developing story-like content because it limits the number of clicks a visitor has to make. Coupled with the increased use of mobile devices, this scrolling trend will remain the design preference of users in 2016.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/scrolllesraffineurs.png" alt="scroll(lesraffineurs)" width="404" height="854" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21170" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.lesraffineurs.com/" target="_blank">lesraffineurs</a></p>
<p><strong>Animations</strong><br />
Well-placed animations can greatly enrich the experience within any web website<br />
Here are some of the most popular: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Loaders: entertains and lets visitors know exactly what’s going on.</li>
<li>Hover: lends itself to a more intuitive user experience, providing user feedback without having to click.</li>
<li>Slideshows: present images and videos without cluttering web design.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/hovercanada.png" alt="hover(canada)" width="845" height="660" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21167" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.canadahouse.es/en/" target="_blank">Canada House</a></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/hoverclick-and-wine-1024x479.png" alt="hover(click and wine)" width="700" height="327" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21168" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.clickandwine.es/gb/" target="_blank">Click and Wine</a></p>
<p>Not all 2015 trends will be along for the ride in 2016. Mona from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/bronze/nurelm">NuRelm</a> says goodbye to: </p>
<p><strong>Flashy but Slow Sites</strong><br />
In 2015, there were many flashy sites that used hefty and sizable parallax styles or large file designs that look cool, but slow down users’ browsers to unbearable speeds. Designs should be clean, unique engaging, and easily accessible, but also easy to process both on the server-side. They should be easy on viewers’ eyes and easy to understand.</p>
<h2 style="color:#1b9743">Design Trends New to 2016</h2>
<p>Each new year brings new ideas. Here are the trends Armando from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/es/asociados-agencia-web/plata/ecomm360">eComm360</a> is most looking forward to in 2016. </p>
<p><strong>Typography</strong><br />
Larger fonts, used expressively, will be more common.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/Tipografiacanadahouse-1024x506.png" alt="Tipografia(canadahouse)" width="700" height="345" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21171" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.canadahouse.es/en/" target="_blank">Canada House</a></p>
<p><strong>Fullscreen</strong><br />
Take advantage of the full width of devices: sliders with multiple images have been replaced with one, high-resolution image. With more advanced technology and improved hardware, larger designs can be better appreciated. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/fullscreentiny-cottons-1024x506.png" alt="fullscreen(tiny cottons)" width="700" height="345" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21165" /></p>
<p><a href="http://tinycottons.com/" target="_blank">Tiny Cottons</a></p>
<p><strong>Burger menu</strong><br />
The Burger menu, so prevalent in responsive designs, is now a regular feature on the websites, even those designed for larger devices. It has long been used for mobile, but as the minimalist trend continues, we see the burger menu replacing traditional dropdowns on desktop. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/menu-hamburguesaclick-and-wine-1024x496.png" alt="menu hamburguesa(click and wine)" width="700" height="339" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21169" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.clickandwine.es/gb/" target="_blank">Click and Wine</a></p>
<p><strong>Ghost buttons</strong><br />
Ghost buttons have been increasingly integrated into today’s design. Virtually invisible, they take minimalism to the extreme. Activated via hover animations, they attract more attention from the user and encourage secondary actions.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/boton-fantasmaimage-republic-1024x487.png" alt="boton fantasma(image republic)" width="700" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21172" /></p>
<p><a href="http://image-republic.com/en/" target="_blank">Image Republic</a></p>
<p><strong>Grid options</strong><br />
Pinterest made this trend popular, and we’ll be seeing it adapted into web design this year. The design works very well when websites need to mix different types of information and invites unlimited and easy content navigation.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/gridtiny-cottons-1024x514.png" alt="grid(tiny cottons)" width="700" height="351" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21166" /></p>
<p><a href="http://tinycottons.com/" target="_blank">Tiny Cottons</a></p>
<p>In 2016, Sam from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/bronze/nurelm">NuRelm</a> is looking forward to: </p>
<p><strong>Accessibility</strong><br />
We are expecting to see a rise in developers and designers implementing designs that  increase usability for those who have trouble accessing a computer or the internet. Whether it be physical touch limitation or sight impairment, new design trends are shifting to adapt to individual needs. We believe everyone should have the right to easily access the internet and browse the same as everyone else, and no company should ignore people that might have trouble browsing their own site.</p>
<h2 style="color:#1b9743">In a nutshell</h2>
<p>Whether you’re an online merchant looking to redesign your website or a designer picking up ideas for new PrestaShop themes, here are a few tips to keep in mind. </p>
<ol>
<li>Design trends should be carefully considered before integrating them into your online shop. The “flashy-er” a trend, the quicker it can potentially die out. If you’re not looking to redesign your shop for a few years, pick the trends you want to integrate wisely.</li>
<li>Don’t forget about your audience, the customer. Regardless of how “cool” your website is, it should ultimately help to convert your customer. Make sure your new design doesn’t detract from the products you’re trying to sell.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-ab-tests-for-optimizing-your-online-store/">A/B test</a> your ideas, if you can. Just because something is trendy, doesn’t mean it will work for your online shop. Make sure that adding these new designs don’t put a damper on your current sales.</li>
</ol>
<p>Looking for some great agencies to give your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/">online store</a> a rocking website design? Pick from our list of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">Official Agencies</a>. Think we missed an important trend for 2016? Share in the comments below!</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6"><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/ecomm360-1024x270.png" alt="ecomm360" width="700" height="184" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13059" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-6"><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/nurelm.png" alt="nurelm" width="220" height="127" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13054" /></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/">2016 Web Design Trends for your Online Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reader Poll: We want to hear from you!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21129</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hi PrestaShop Community, Help us to create the perfect blog for you. The questions will take you 2 minutes. The answers will give you great ecommerce content for the rest of the year. Take the survey! Thank you and Happy Selling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/">Reader Poll: We want to hear from you!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi PrestaShop Community, </p>
<p>Help us to create the perfect blog for you. The questions will take you 2 minutes. The answers will give you great ecommerce content for the rest of the year.</p>
<div class="text-center" style="margin-bottom: 20px"><a href="https://jliu08ps.typeform.com/to/iE9Vzy" target="_blank" style="font-size:23px">Take the survey!</a></div>
<p>Thank you and Happy Selling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/">Reader Poll: We want to hear from you!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Valentine’s day is just around the corner. Lovers and relationship hopefuls will spend an estimated $18.9 billion (according to NRF) on gifts, dinners and more on the big day. With customers in love and ready to spend, here are 5 steps you can count to help you reach successful Valentine’s day sales. 1. Think Mobile [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/">5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Valentine’s day is just around the corner. Lovers and relationship hopefuls will spend an estimated <a href="https://nrf.com/media/press-releases/cupid-shower-americans-jewelry-candy-this-valentines-day" target="_blank">$18.9 billion (according to NRF)</a> on gifts, dinners and more on the big day. With customers in love and ready to spend, here are 5 steps you can count to help you reach successful Valentine’s day sales.<br />
<span id="more-21140"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">1. Think Mobile</h2>
<p>Mobile is fast becoming the preferred shopping channel in leading ecommerce markets like the UK and Germany. With <a href="http://resources.mobify.com/50-mobile-commerce-stats.html" target="_blank">30% of customers saying they’ll abandon a mobile</a> purchase if the site isn’t optimized, you would do well to make this a priority during peak sales periods like Valentine’s Day. Make sure your emails are adapted to mobile viewing, and that the transition from email to site to checkout is seamless. If your website isn’t mobile-responsive already, make that first on your list of things to do to get ready for the sales season.</p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">2. Create an attractive offer</h2>
<p>As with other sale periods, the challenge at Valentine’s Day is to come up with an offer that stands out from the crowd. Merchants who sell traditional Valentine’s Day goods like flowers, chocolates, stuffed animals and lingerie will be under exceptional pressure to catch the consumer eye. Discounts are an obvious option, but playing on price alone can be hit or miss. Consider offering <a href="https://www.ice-watch.com/uk-en/ice-sili/ice-love-p-26729.htm?coul_att_detailID=1266&amp;utm_source=B2C+-+Customers+-+Contacts+-+Ice-Watch&amp;utm_campaign=97b098e6ae-2016_01_14_love_teaser_ALL_ALL&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_b847164ea2-97b098e6ae-273191485&amp;mc_cid=97b098e6ae&amp;mc_eid=754b62a6a1" target="_blank">limited edition items</a> or custom product bundles that play on a sense of urgency and the current holiday theme. </p>
<p>Another option is to combine attractive sales with personalized marketing efforts. Valentine’s Day is stressful for some people, so offering an added value in the form of gift guides, curation, or even a vamped up live chat can be the detail that convinces customers to shop with you. Think about what problem or desire your products respond to, and then focus on getting that message to your customers via your blog, newsletter and email campaigns. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">3. Promote</h2>
<p>After you’ve come up with the perfect offer, make sure customers are aware of your sale. Here are a few suggestions:</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/"><strong>Pop Ups or Pop Ins</strong></a><br />
Pop-ups and pop-ins promote your sale to people who are already on your website. Because they take up your entire web page, they’re sure to capture shoppers’ attention&#8211; but they can also be seen as disruptive. Be sure to place limitations on the number of times a shopper will receive the prompt so they don’t leave with a bad impression.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-awesome-ideas-valentines-day-gift-guides/"><strong>Gift Guides</strong></a><br />
Gift guides are a versatile way to promote your products. They’re especially helpful for shoppers who are stymied for gift ideas, or who waited until the last minute. A well put-together gift guide directs shoppers with different needs to the perfect present. If you have a blog, use it to showcase your products to your readers. Consider putting together an advice-based post that gives customers added value in addition to presenting your product.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/"><strong>Email Marketing</strong></a><br />
Email remains one of the most effective ways of getting your message out: you reach directly into your customer’s inbox for a chance to grab their attention and drive traffic to your website. Be sure you have a catchy subject line to reel them in, and that the transition from inbox to landing page goes off without a hitch. Depending on your promotion, you might also consider a multi-tiered email campaign that divides the focus between price-based offers and <a href="http://www.splio4.com/mr/6fU0is7q4/3390/1877180697.html" target="_blank">unique value adds</a> that are likely to differentiate you from the competition. Think about how you can delight your customer this year, in addition to saving her money.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-launching-sem-campaign-google-adwords/"><strong>Google Ads</strong></a><br />
This is potentially the most costly promotion tool in your marketing kit. Whether you manage your campaign directly with Google Adwords, or use a third-party service provider, you’ll have to pay to use this option. Around holiday sales, bids for keywords like “Valentine’s Day” and “Gifts” tend to be higher. However, the visibility you will gain has great earning potential for your website. You should evaluate your resources and allocate budget accordingly; Google Ads can be a great boost, but if you don’t have a compelling offer or give customers a reason to trust you, then no amount of traffic will help you reach your sales goals.</p>
<p>- <strong>Website banner displays</strong><br />
Just like popups and popins, website banners only promote your sale to people already shopping on your site. The advantage is that a banner is not as intrusive, and unlike popups and popins, customers can’t simply close and forget about them. (Here&#8217;s how to change them with the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/">default template</a>). They’re a great place to use theme-specific images and highlight perks like free shipping and gift wrapping. Think about adding in a shipping cut off reminder as well. Everything you do to simplify the shopping experience gets you a step closer to a conversion.</p>
<p>- <strong>Social Media</strong><br />
Promoting your sale on social media is a great way to reach shoppers who are interested but haven’t made a purchase with you. It’s also a great opportunity for your ad to be shared among shoppers’ online friends. You might consider a social-only promotion or contest to drum up interest.</p>
<p>Do you know you plan on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/">promoting your valentine&#8217;s day sales</a>? For more help and advice, check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/">Valentine&#8217;s Day Marketing</a> article! </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">4. Test</h2>
<p>With a limited time to convert customers, it’s important to test your website and the offers that you’ve developed. Make sure the coupons and promotions you’re promoting actually work: it sounds obvious, but when you’re rushing to get things just right and in time, there’s always a possibility of a technical error slipping in. Don’t wait to find out on the day of the sale.</p>
<p>Besides testing your promotions, here are a few other tasks you should complete before you launch your sale: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Test links from all your advertising</li>
<li>Try placing an order (this is especially critical when you allow customers to customize products)</li>
<li>Complete the order with each of your payment options. There is nothing worse than having a customer discard a purchase because they were unable to pay.</li>
</ul>
<p>Valentine’s Day is a big one for last-minute orders, so it’s more important than ever to ensure quick and easy ordering. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">5. Analyze</h2>
<p>Last, but certainly not least: schedule time for post-holiday sales analysis. Use this time to review your sales predictions and to see if the sales met or fell short of your target goals. Ask yourself questions like: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What worked well this year?</li>
<li>What can be improved?</li>
<li>Which trends would we like to test for the next holiday sale?</li>
<li>Which trends were surprising and warrant another look?</li>
<li>Which ideas, if any, should we stop testing?</li>
</ul>
<p>The conclusions you draw from your analysis will be important for making predictions for your next sales holiday. It&#8217;s also important to analyze the products you have leftover and brainstorm another promotion to clear this year&#8217;s Valentine&#8217;s Day products. </p>
<hr width="20%" align="left" />
<p>Are you ready for Valentine&#8217;s day 2016? Share any tips you’ve learned in the comments or come back and tell us how these steps helped you achieve your sales goal this year! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/">5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
